Guide to the Mack Buckley Swearingen papers,1920-1969.
Swearingen, Mack Buckley papers, 1920-1969.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mack Buckley Swearingen papers, 1920-1969.
2637
Mack Buckley Swearingen 1902-1969.
22.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, typescripts, clippings, correspondence, journals, photographs, audiotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes personal and professional correspondence, material related to Swearingen's career as professor of history. Pamphlets, books, articles, research materials, essays, book reviews, photographs, cartoons, tapes, radio broadcasts, speeches, material concerning Vietnam and Turkey, journals, and other records. Also, genealogical material, and draft of Swearingen's unpublished book about Turkey. Correspondents include Flannery O'Connor and Eudora Welty.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Mack Buckley Swearingen was a native of Mississippi and received his B.A. there from Millsaps College. He studied at Oxford University as a Rhodes scholar and earned his Ph.D. at the University of Chicago. He taught history at Elmira College for 24 years until 1966, then at Lake Erie College in Painesville, Ohio for two years. From 1955 to 1957 he taught in Turkey on a Rockefeller Foundation grant.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes personal and professional correspondence, course schedules, rosters, student letters, and other material related to Swearingen's career as professor of history. Also, pamphlets, books, articles, research materials, essays, book reviews, photographs, cartoons, tapes, radio broadcasts, speeches, material concerning Vietnam and Turkey, journals, and other records. Also, genealogical material, and draft of Swearingen's unpublished book about Turkey, text with black and white photographs. Correspondents include Flannery O'Connor and Eudora Welty.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Swearingen, Mack Buckley,1902-1969.; O'Connor, Flannery.; Welty, Eudora, 1909-; Elmira College.; Lake Erie College.
Subjects:
History--Study and teaching.; College teachers--United States.
Places:
Turkey.; Vietnam.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
List of Correspondents:
Anreassen, John Christian Ludwig
Arthur, Stanley Clisby
Ashby, Warren
Atwater, Elton
Aydelotte, Frank
Ballard, Marshall
Beale, Howard Kennedy
Beard, Mary Ritter (Mrs. Charles A.)
Beasley, A. Joe
Bechtel, Edward Ambrose
Beck, Charlton T.
Bell, Tartt
Bernt, Hans H., and Mary
Binkley, William
Blair, John Malcolm
Brown, C. Victor
Bowers, Claude Gernade
Bratton, Theodore Du Bose, Bishop
Brown, Elwin R.
Bryan, Harry M.
Burrell, Sidney Alexander
Carman, Harry James
Carroll, Joseph W.
Chalmers, Allan Knight
Carter, Hodding
Chambers, Moreau
Clausen, Joyce Anne (Mrs. William Sterling Roby III)
Coffin, Foster
Coghill, Nevill
Cole, Fred Carrington
Coleman, Roy V.
Collins, Henry Bascom Jr.
Conwell, Walter Lichtenhaeler
Cooper, Tim E.
Craven, Avery Odelle
Crawford, Edward Aiken
Crittendon, William Clark
Cross, Whitney Rogers
Destler, Chester McArthur, and Katherine
Dewey, Malcolm Howard
Dodd, Martha Eccles (Mrs. Alfred Kaufman Stern)
Dodd, William Edward
Drake, William Edward
Dreyfous, George Abel
Drinkwater, Geneva
Duffy, Joseph Alexander Jr.
Dunbar, Charles Edward Jr.
Eldred, Lewis
Fichman, David
Fletcher, John Madison
Fletcher, Louise
Fulbright, James William
Furry, Edward B.
Gates, Paul Wallace
Girelius, Charles G.
Gottschalk, Louis
Graham, Frank Porter
Green, Fletcher Melvin
Greene, Helen (Helen Finch)
Grieder, Elmer
Guild, Eugene
Hamer, Philip May
Hamilton, Charles Granville
Hamilton, Joseph Gregoire de Roulhac
Hamilton, William Baskerville
Hansen, Ann M.
Harcourt, Guy Nichols
Harris, Rufus Carrolton
Hayes, Helen
Hays, Brooks
Hewitt, Thomas M.
Hicks, Frederick Cyril Nugent
Himstead, Ralph Ebner
Hizlilar, Julide S.
Holloway, Vernon Howard
Holton, Holland
Hooper, Frances
Hoover, Herbert
Horton, Myles
Humphreys, Rena Lloyd
Jack, Theodore Henley
Jacklin, Kathleen
Jamesson, James Reynold Paul von Reinhold III (Asia House)
Jerry, Harold A.
Jiggitts, Louis Meredith
Jones, George Hilton
Junker, Louis J.
Kalif, George Todd
Kellar, Herbert Anthony
Kercher, Leonard Clayton
Kern, Alfred Allan
Key, David Martin
Knappen, Marshall Mason
Knopf, Alfred A.
Korman, Gerd
Kreeger, M. M.
Lach, Donald Frederick
Laney, Frank Miller Jr.
Lang, Sam
Langley, Billie Lee (in Saudi Arabia)
Largent, Robert J., and Virginia Rider
Ledet, Wilton Paul
Lee, Harold Newton
Levy, Benjamin Franklin
Light, Nancy
Lin, James Reese
Longino, Andrew Houston
Longino, James Marion
Longstreet, Helen Dortch
Lord, Clifford Lee
Lyon, Elijah Wilson
McCain, William David
McCutcheon, Roger Philip
Macdonald of the Isles, Celia [ck. Burke's Peerage]
McKnight, Martha L. Kemp, and Theodore P.
McLean, Ross Hanlin
MacMurtrie, Douglas Crawford
Marshall, John
Mayo, Bernard
Meadows, John Cassius
Merrill, Horace Samuel
Miller, John D.
Mills, Ethel M.
Mills, Floy Gilmore (Mrs. Walter)
Milton, George Fort
Mitch, Frank
Mitchell, Williams M.
Moore, Albert Burton
Moore, Edith Wyatt
Murrah, William Belton, Bishop
Murray, John Ralph
Newman, Linda
Nixon, Nicholas Clarence
Northrup, Barbara Winifred
Odum, Howard Washington
Oswald, Lowell
Parmly, George
Patton, James Welch
Pilcher, Dudley
Pipkin, Charles Wooten
Pott, William Sumner Appleton
Prichard, Walter
Queen, Merritt, B.
Raines, Merle
Ramsdell, Charles William
Reed, John
Ries, Maurice
Ritchie, Kathryn Anne
Robbe, Charles W.
Roberts, J. L.
Roche, Sybil O'Grady
Rowell, L. S.
Rowland, Dunbar
Ryder, (Lady) Frances
Sallee, Mary Owens
Sanborn, Frederic R.
Sanders, Albert Godfrey
Schevill, Ferdinand
Shugg, Roger Wallace
Sidel, James E.
Silin, Charles Intervale
Slesinger, Donald
Smith, Howard Kingsbury
Snow, Royall Henderson
Speight, Harold Edwin Balme
Stark, Alice L. Lehmann (Mrs. Alexander T. Stark)
Stephenson, Wendell Holmes
Sticker, William Hugh
Strom, Carl Walther
Swartwood, Howard Albright
Snydor, Charles Sackett
Taylor, Horace "Hoy"
Ten Hoor, Marten
Thompson, Merle Dow, and Louise H.
Thompson, Robert H.
Tolbert, Jack
Turnbull, William Watson
Utley, Clifton Maxwell
Valentine, Alan
Van Graafeiland, Ruth M.
Von der Lancken, Carl
Walden, Earl
Walley, Willis
Walmsley, T. Semmes
Walsh, Warren Bartlett
Warren, Robert Penn
Warner, W. Lloyd
Weaver, William N.
Webb, Helmer Lewis
Webb, Walter Prescott
Wells, Guy Herbert
Weltner, Philip
White, Ann Woodhouse (Mrs. David Platt White)
White, Hugh Lawson
Wilkins, Josephine
Wilson, Arthur McCandless
Wilson, Charles
Wisner, Elizabeth
Woellner, Robert Carlton
Woody, Robert Hilliard
Wylie, (Sir) Francis James
SERIES LIST
Series I. General Files
Boxes 1 - 22
Series II. Flannery O'Connor Correspondence
Box 23
Series III. Eudora Welty Correspondence
Box 23
Series IV. Audiotapes
Box 24
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General Files
  - Letters by Sherwood Eddy re: Sharecroppers and Delta Cooperative Farm, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poindexter Research - includes copies of Washington Republican and later papers, 1813-1817 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Typescripts of letters for Poindexter Thesis, 1818-1820 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carbon Draft of Thesis - "The New Scene" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Editorials and drafts, 1808-1809 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings re: Jackson, Mississippi, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mounted Items - Mississippi, 1809-1832 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mounted Items - Mississippi, Poindexter et al (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mounted Items - Natchez (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notes re: Mississsippi (quotations) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Poindexter Genealogical Notes, 1860-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Drafts of Thesis (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Material for Bibliographies (including 1931 Correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carbon Draft and Other Material about Natchez (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Maps and Pictures of Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Napoleon and the Ottoman Empire" Term Paper by MBS, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "An Investigation of the Similarity Between the Resolutions of Calhoun and Davis", 1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photo of Poindexter by St. Memin, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings about Memphis, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newsclippings - Misc., 1925-1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newsclippings about Battle of Lexington, MA, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Article - "Booth's Letter to Grant", 1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Broadside - "To the People of Natchez and Adams County", 1841 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Articles about Jackson, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mounted Clippings of Miss., Related Items and MBS, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "People's Rights Bulletin" - North Carolina, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "On History" - manuscript, typescript, and draft, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Bowers' Study" bibliography notes, correspondence - Claude G. Bowers, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Claude Gernade Bowers: A Critical Study" by MBS, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Causes of War - Final Report of Study on French Armaments" by MBS, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Causes of War" Misc. Notes (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "The Mecklenburg Declaration of Independence" by MBS (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "The Rhodes Scholar at Oxford, A Dissenting View" by MBS, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Newsclippings by and about MBS, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Newsclippings by and about Tulane and MBS, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Tulane Controversy" letter and clipping, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Tulane Fight" Newspaper clippings and correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Student letters home, 1924 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Student letters home, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
  - Student letters home, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Student letters home, 1927 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence (see end of guide for complete list of people included in folders), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "The Life of George Poindexter - A Story of the First Southwest" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Russia - Torch Club Paper (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Dodo and Other Extinct Birds" Student League for Industrial Democracy - Tulane - Talk on Liberalism, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "In Anticipation of Trouble, Because...", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Street of Knives" (review protested by MBS) and "The Trouble at Hungerfords", 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Executive Power" YWCA Paper (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Contemporary Georgia - Misc. Material, 1941-9142 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "College and the Dilemma of Leadership" (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Education and Recovery" talk for A.A.U.W. meeting, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Church and Patriotism" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "An Approach to International Relations", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Talk for Youth Mass Meeting - "Who Wins Wars?", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "States' Rights" radio address, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letter to Gov. White re: Institutes of Higher Learning in Mississippi, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with Charles Dunbar, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Discipline and the Social Order" (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "The Church and Free Speech" (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Genesis of Social Revolution" paper for New Orleans Academy of Sciences, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Fighting Communism the Right Way" (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Russian Speech - Binghamton Torch Club, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Library Radio Program for Steele Memorial Library, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Remarks to the Freshman Class (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "The South and Civil Rights" for the League of Women Voters (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Towanda Speech (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "The English Mind" (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "How to Pick a Political Party" (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "We Have With Us Today..." (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "The Press and I" (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Maxon Paper, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "A New Oval Window" MBS Ear Operation (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Torch Club Paper II (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Geography and Culture" (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clippings - misc., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Preface for Historians, for Students, Chapter I book on American History (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Term Papers, manuscript drafts, notes (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Edward Carter Turner Diary, 1862-1863 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Whitmore Diary, 1835-1861 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - War Labor Board - Correspondence, Reports, etc., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Photostats (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Endicott Johnson re: Legal Case, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - War Labor Board - Andover Motors case, etc., 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Andover Case, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Southern Clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Lee Clippings, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Delta Democrat Times-Lee Reprint, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Lee's Second Editorial in Reply to Critics, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Carter Editorial on Sprigle, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle II (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle III (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle IV (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle V (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Carter's Reply to Sprigle VI (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Clippings about Henry Wallace, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - 39th District, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters on Public Affairs, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - McGehee, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PTA, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Old American and English History Exam Questions (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hayes Memorial, 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Knopf, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rhodes Scholarship Application papers, 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Communist Material, 1935-1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Southern Politics, 1936-1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Birmingham - article, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Southern Politics (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Confessions of a College Teacher", 1933 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "The Radical's Betrayal" by Johan J. Smertenko, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "The Supreme Court and the New Deal" by Mitchell Dawson, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "The Riddle of the Reichstag Fire" by Anonymous, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "The Road to Destitution" by C. Hartley Grattan, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Hitlerism Comes to America" by J. J. Smertenko, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "To Tell or Not to Tell" by Eugene Lyons, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Aliens and Alien Baiters" by Louis Adamic, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "What Hitler Wants" by Leon Trotsky, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "The Betrayal of Cleveland" by John T. Flynn (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "The Wall Street Pump" by John T. Flynn, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Men Like War" by Leo C. Rosten, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "The Evolution of Business Groupings" by Clarence E. Bonnett, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Civil Liberty, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Social Security Act (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Farm Tenancy, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Psychologists and War, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ford vs. CIO, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Socialist Material, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Students' Term Papers, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - The Nuremburg Laws, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "Culture in the Third Realm" by Otis Lee, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Asquith's War Chronology, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Unclassified, 1936-1946 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Evangeline Park, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - M. Ries and Ft. de la Boulaye, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - "Background for War", 1939 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Clippings - Personal, 1936-1946 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sanborn Check, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Robert H. Thompson Commission, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Washburn Storage Co., 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Official Records - Chicago and Oxford, 1923-1932 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Income Tax, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - War Service Act, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Russian Government (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Parties and Elections, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Finding Lists - Louisiana Material, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Smith - Acculturation, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Contemporary Issues - Misc., 1928-1941 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Brisbane, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Association Publications - Public Affairs, etc. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Bower's Democratic Keynote, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Civil Liberties, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Crack Pot Material, 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - YWCA - Postwar Discussion Material, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - "Farewell, My Lovely!", 1936 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - "Eddie Stands for Good Clean Sport", 1933 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - It Seems to Me..., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Georgia University, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - New Llano, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Progressive - On New Orleans, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - English History Notes (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ramsdell - Reconstruction (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Map Studies (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - English History - General (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - American History Notes (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Miscellaneous - Mississippi (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Bismarck and Cavour (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Oxford Tutorial Essays - Foreign (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Dodd's Lectures on the South (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Fernegan on Historical Research Class notes (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Thompson - Absolute Monarchy (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - European History Vacancy, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contemporary Civilization, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Political Scientist, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Official, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Political Science, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Political Science, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - New Economist, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - New York Historical, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Class Schedules, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Term Paper Methods (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Academic Statute, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Comprehensive Examinations, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Student and Field, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Special Committee on Education, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tenure Rule - Elmira, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Educational Policies Committee, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bernt - Book Requests, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Comptroller's Office, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - College Business, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Applications, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Division of Community Education, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Political Scientist, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Class of 1948, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Iris - Elmira College Yearbook, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Quarter System (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Division - Correspondence and Schedules, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Veterans, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Division of Community Education, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Requisitions, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Comptroller's Office, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Official, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Official, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Princeton Quiz, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Bulletins, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Comptroller's Office, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Historical Records Committee, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Official, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "Dome of Holy Wisdom" (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Turkish Information Office, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Department of State - Turkey, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Turkey Notes, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Turkey Newsclippings, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Inaugural Lecture at Ankara University, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Clippings - Turkey, 1956-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Family, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - TAA (Turkish American Association), 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Personal - Misc., 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Phiebig - Book Orders, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Harold Jerry, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Zealand, Australia, Philippines - Conference Board and Department of State, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - John Marshall, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Turkish Appointment, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence - Turkey, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ankara University, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Business - Turkey, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Personal, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Family, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Personal, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lecture Series I (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lecture Series II (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ear Operation, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Turkey, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Broadcast, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Broadcast, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Broadcast, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Broadcast, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Broadcast, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - On Frank Graham (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Apologia (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - College - Letters, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "So You've Come to College" Speech (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Two Loose Carbon Manuscripts (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Notes - Personal, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Social Studies 101-102, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - College Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Evening and Summer Sessions, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Peace Corps, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Family Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Social Science Division, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Social Science Division, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Junior Year Abroad, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Social Studies 101-102, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - College - Official, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Typescripts, manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Family Letters, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Personal, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Personal Letters, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - No Title - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tax, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - No Title - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Family, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Family, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters - All Kinds, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - No Title - Mostly Family, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Family, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Letters - All Kinds, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Personal, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Junior Year Abroad, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Poindexter (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "The Whole Person" play (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "The Whole Person" Act I (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Act II Sutter (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Act III (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Act II Scene 2 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - First Draft (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Act III (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Act III (carbon) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Odd Pages (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Act II Scene I (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Act I First Draft (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Cornell, 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Vermont, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Purchase of Old South Materials, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 27)